<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-06-11T15:19:29+01:00</updated><id>https://big-culture.github.io//feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ron Herrema talk</title><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//2024/ron-herrema/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ron Herrema talk"/><published>2024-06-11T15:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-06-11T15:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://big-culture.github.io//2024/ron-herrema</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://big-culture.github.io//2024/ron-herrema/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="about-the-talk">About the Talk</h1> <p>In this talk, I would like to take a phenomenological approach to the investigation of my 25+ years of experience writing computer code as a means of composing music and generating musical experience. In so doing, I will touch on a range of topics - including Code as Prosthesis, Lisp (List Processing), Sp/ARC (Specification and Audiation in Real-Time Composition), and Composing in the Continuum – and attempt to integrate this ‘dog’s breakfast’ within a wholistic experience that is rooted in – or at least related to - Taoist philosophy.</p> <h1 id="about-the-speaker">About the Speaker</h1> <p><a href="https://ronherrema.net/">Ron Herrema</a> is a composer, digital multi-artist, and app developer. In recent years he has focused on live coding as both performer and researcher; he has also developed multiple app/artworks for mobile devices; co-produced the winning entry at The Tate Modern’s art hackathon; performed audiovisual free improv; composed for film; and created an interactive installation for the Tate Britain. He has been especially interested in integrating contemplative practices with technology and creativity, and is a certified teacher of Deep Listening. Currently residing in Bath, England, he is a Michigan native and received his PhD in composition from Michigan State University. He worked as a full-time lecturer at Northeastern University and at De Montfort University, followed by several years of working as a freelance creative technologist in London. For the past eight years, he has worked as a Senior Lecturer in Creative Computing at Bath Spa University.</p> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/speakers/herrema_ron-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/speakers/herrema_ron-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/speakers/herrema_ron-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/speakers/herrema_ron.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="talks"/><category term="event"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we had a talk from Ron Herrema on a phenomenological approach to writing computer code]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intersensory data representations of a black hole</title><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//2024/black-hole/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intersensory data representations of a black hole"/><published>2024-06-04T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-06-04T16:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://big-culture.github.io//2024/black-hole</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://big-culture.github.io//2024/black-hole/"><![CDATA[<p>Redirect to <a href="https://quest.mit.edu/news/intersensory-data-representations-black-hole">https://quest.mit.edu/news/intersensory-data-representations-black-hole</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interesting reading about Dr. Kyle Keane's research]]></summary></entry></feed>