<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-03-26T00:24:58+00:00</updated><id>https://big-culture.github.io//feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">a post with image galleries</title><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/photo-gallery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with image galleries"/><published>2024-12-04T00:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-04T00:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/photo-gallery</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/photo-gallery/"><![CDATA[<p>The images in this post are all zoomable, arranged into different mini-galleries using different libraries.</p> <h2 id="lightbox2"><a href="https://lokeshdhakar.com/projects/lightbox2/">Lightbox2</a></h2> <p><a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/></a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="photoswipe"><a href="https://photoswipe.com/">PhotoSwipe</a></h2> <div class="pswp-gallery pswp-gallery--single-column" id="gallery--getting-started"> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="1669" data-pswp-height="2500" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/7/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="1875" data-pswp-height="2500" data-cropped="true" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/7/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <a href="https://unsplash.com" data-pswp-src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="2500" data-pswp-height="1666" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <div> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="2500" data-pswp-height="1667" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> </div> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="spotlight-js"><a href="https://nextapps-de.github.io/spotlight/">Spotlight JS</a></h2> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/4/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/4/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/5/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/5/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-200.jpg"/> </a> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="venobox"><a href="https://veno.es/venobox/">Venobox</a></h2> <p><a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="images"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included image galleries could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ron Herrema talk</title><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/ron-herrema/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ron Herrema talk"/><published>2024-06-11T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-11T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/ron-herrema</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/ron-herrema/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="about-the-talk">About the Talk</h1> <p>In this talk, I would like to take a phenomenological approach to the investigation of my 25+ years of experience writing computer code as a means of composing music and generating musical experience. In so doing, I will touch on a range of topics - including Code as Prosthesis, Lisp (List Processing), Sp/ARC (Specification and Audiation in Real-Time Composition), and Composing in the Continuum – and attempt to integrate this ‘dog’s breakfast’ within a wholistic experience that is rooted in – or at least related to - Taoist philosophy.</p> <h1 id="about-the-speaker">About the Speaker</h1> <p><a href="https://ronherrema.net/">Ron Herrema</a> is a composer, digital multi-artist, and app developer. In recent years he has focused on live coding as both performer and researcher; he has also developed multiple app/artworks for mobile devices; co-produced the winning entry at The Tate Modern’s art hackathon; performed audiovisual free improv; composed for film; and created an interactive installation for the Tate Britain. He has been especially interested in integrating contemplative practices with technology and creativity, and is a certified teacher of Deep Listening. Currently residing in Bath, England, he is a Michigan native and received his PhD in composition from Michigan State University. He worked as a full-time lecturer at Northeastern University and at De Montfort University, followed by several years of working as a freelance creative technologist in London. For the past eight years, he has worked as a Senior Lecturer in Creative Computing at Bath Spa University.</p> <h1 id="the-talk">The Talk</h1> <p>A piano piece, of Latin roots. It waxes and wanes through Spanish refrains, all the while evoking a reflective mood. But it is playful and urges a foot tap or a head sway that would evolve into a dance if you let it. Perfect for a piece named Baile…</p> <p>This is how our inaugural BIG Culture guest talk, with Dr Ron Herrema on contemplative practices in computing and composition, commenced. Drawing on his background in music composition and computer science, Ron guided us through his personal history as well a whistle-stop tour of algorithmic composing, highlighting the stand-out figures in the field as well as his own personal mentors and heroes.</p> <p>His tale begins at church, in a Dutch Calvinist environment which he left long ago, where he sat in contemplation whilst music played at the beginning of service. Ron recounted this as his first encounter with the concept of contemplation and its relation to music. However, the idea became tangible in the form of <em>New Seed of Contemplation</em> by Thomas Merton, which encouraged him to actively think about contemplation as a practice. Moving into University and beyond, with a BA from Calvin College, Ron was mentored by Pauline Oliveros (1932-2016) who developed the practice of Deep Listening:</p> <p><em>“Deep Listening…explores the difference between the involuntary nature of hearing and the conscious nature of listening. The practice includes bodywork, sonic meditations, and interactive performance…“</em></p> <p>Dr Herrema would eventually become a practitioner himself. He pointed out that Pauline had a practice of opening up her accordion first and just “letting it breathe” before playing even a single note. This practice of Deep Listening flowered the ideas of engaging in contemplation whilst playing music that had germinated whilst he had sat in church as a child. His next teacher was Laozi, through his seminal work the <em>Tao Te Ching</em>. It appealed to a longstanding fascination that Ron had about the relationship between efficiency and ease, which he believed was articulated in The Way, the core of Taoist practice:</p> <p>“<em>…the Great Way is easy…</em>”</p> <p>In simple terms, Ron wanted to study how the least amount of effort could accomplish the most amount of things, in the context of his composition and coding. This, combined with his study of contemplation, lead to questions such as: are coding and composition contemplative practices? When can we say ‘the Great Way is easy’? How can we flow?</p> <p>Having linked his background in composition with coding via the Tao, Dr Herrema dove into his history with computing. His first exposure to computers was the Commodore 64 in ‘84, followed by Apple IIe in ‘85 and the Atari 520 ST in ‘87. Having come across Leon Brodie’s <em>Starting Forth</em>, he embarked on learning a language whose foundational syntactical unit was the word, alluding to the theological idea of the divine Logos. Ron then pointed out that he was attracted to Forth because of its terseness, which could have potentially related to his understanding of the Great Way. Following on from this Ron would briefly discuss the early compositional software and hardware that he encountered such as Dr T’s music software (a keyboard controlled sequencer) and UPIC (a graphic synthesis system) which was developed by Iannis Xenakis in his studio at Paris.</p> <p>Dr Herrema then explored his early history of algorithmic composition, focusing on pieces such as <em>Analogies</em> (2001 which was made using AC Toolbox) - a lisp (list processing) based software developed by Paul Berg. This piece was preceded by <em>Changing Weights</em> in (2000) which is also the name of a function in AC Toolbox. His more recent works involve <em>Music for Being</em> (2012), <em>Dancing Wu Wei</em> and <em>Infinity</em> (2017), developed using Reaktor and OpenFrameworks in conjunction with AC Toolbox. Following <em>Infinity</em> Ron accepted the Southwest Creative Technology Network Automation Fellowship (2018-2019). His primary research as part of this Fellowship:</p> <p>Dr Herrema then explored his early history of algorithmic composition, focusing on pieces such as <em>Analogies</em> (2001 which was made using AC Toolbox) - a lisp (list processing) based software developed by Paul Berg. This piece was preceded by <em>Changing Weights</em> in (2000) which is also the name of a function in AC Toolbox. His more recent works involve <em>Music for Being</em> (2012), <em>Dancing Wu Wei</em> and <em>Infinity</em> (2017), developed using Reaktor and OpenFrameworks in conjunction with AC Toolbox. Following <em>Infinity</em> Ron accepted the Southwest Creative Technology Network Automation Fellowship (2018-2019). His primary research as part of this Fellowship:</p> <p>This, compounded by his encounter with <em>Understanding Media - The Extensions of Man</em> by Marshall MacLuhan lead to the development of <em>Code as Prosthesis</em> , a practice led research project. Why prosthesis? Etymologically, prosthesis finds its roots in prostithenai, from pros ‘in addition’ + tithenai ‘to a place’. The question beneath the question was: when does a tool become a prosthesis, to which Ron provided the following answer:</p> <p>“<em>When it becomes so integrated into one’s self as a means of sensing and controlling some dimension of the world, that it begins to function as part of oneself.</em>”</p> <p>Following on from the establishment of the project and the answering of his initial questions, Dr Herrema moved onto his next project <em>Sp/ARC</em> - Specification and Audiation in Real-time Composition (2020-2021). This project had three aims:</p> <p>Following on from the establishment of the project and the answering of his initial questions, Dr Herrema moved onto his next project <em>Sp/ARC</em> - Specification and Audiation in Real-time Composition (2020-2021). This project had three aims:</p> <ul> <li>Develop series of templates for rapid creation of mobile audio software.</li> <li>Create an app that facilitates real time composition, including the ability to easily disseminate it.</li> <li>To create a beautiful interface. This was followed by a live demo of the software. Ron proceeded to wrap up the talk by discussing how undertaking the project helped answer the following questions for him:</li> </ul> <p><em>How does one meet the self in one’s practice?</em></p> <p>Listening inwardly and by engaging in one’s practice contemplatively.</p> <p><em>When can we say the great way is easy?</em></p> <p>When the simplicity of one’s tools are matched by their power and when they have become an extension of one’s self.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="talks"/><category term="event"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we had a talk from Ron Herrema on a phenomenological approach to writing computer code]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intersensory data representations of a black hole</title><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/black-hole/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intersensory data representations of a black hole"/><published>2024-06-04T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-04T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/black-hole</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/black-hole/"><![CDATA[<p>Redirect to <a href="https://quest.mit.edu/news/intersensory-data-representations-black-hole">https://quest.mit.edu/news/intersensory-data-representations-black-hole</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interesting reading about Dr. Kyle Keane's research]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[<p>May 14, 2024[[read-time]] min read We’re introducing a series of updates across the Gemini family of models, including the new 1.5 Flash, our lightweight model for speed and efficiency, and Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants. In December, we launched our first natively multimodal model Gemini 1.0 in three sizes: Ultra, Pro and Nano. Just a few months later we released 1.5 Pro, with enhanced performance and a breakthrough long context window of 1 million tokens.Developers and enterprise customers have been putting 1.5 Pro to use in incredible ways and finding its long context window, multimodal reasoning capabilities and impressive overall performance incredibly useful.We know from user feedback that some applications need lower latency and a lower cost to serve. This inspired us to keep innovating, so today, we’re introducing Gemini 1.5 Flash: a model that’s lighter-weight than 1.5 Pro, and designed to be fast and efficient to serve at scale.Both 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash are available in public preview with a 1 million token context window in Google AI Studio and Vertex AI. And now, 1.5 Pro is also available with a 2 million token context window via waitlist to developers using the API and to Google Cloud customers.We’re also introducing updates across the Gemini family of models, announcing our next generation of open models, Gemma 2, and sharing progress on the future of AI assistants, with Project Astra.Context lengths of leading foundation models compared with Gemini 1.5’s 2 million token capability1.5 Flash is the newest addition to the Gemini model family and the fastest Gemini model served in the API. It’s optimized for high-volume, high-frequency tasks at scale, is more cost-efficient to serve and features our breakthrough long context window.While it’s a lighter weight model than 1.5 Pro, it’s highly capable of multimodal reasoning across vast amounts of information and delivers impressive quality for its size.The new Gemini 1.5 Flash model is optimized for speed and efficiency, is highly capable of multimodal reasoning and features our breakthrough long context window.1.5 Flash excels at summarization, chat applications, image and video captioning, data extraction from long documents and tables, and more. This is because it’s been trained by 1.5 Pro through a process called “distillation,” where the most essential knowledge and skills from a larger model are transferred to a smaller, more efficient model.Read more about 1.5 Flash in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report, on the Gemini technology page, and learn about 1.5 Flash’s availability and pricing.Over the last few months, we’ve significantly improved 1.5 Pro, our best model for general performance across a wide range of tasks.Beyond extending its context window to 2 million tokens, we’ve enhanced its code generation, logical reasoning and planning, multi-turn conversation, and audio and image understanding through data and algorithmic advances. We see strong improvements on public and internal benchmarks for each of these tasks.1.5 Pro can now follow increasingly complex and nuanced instructions, including ones that specify product-level behavior involving role, format and style. We’ve improved control over the model’s responses for specific use cases, like crafting the persona and response style of a chat agent or automating workflows through multiple function calls. And we’ve enabled users to steer model behavior by setting system instructions.We added audio understanding in the Gemini API and Google AI Studio, so 1.5 Pro can now reason across image and audio for videos uploaded in Google AI Studio. And we’re now integrating 1.5 Pro into Google products, including Gemini Advanced and in Workspace apps.Read more about 1.5 Pro in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report and on the Gemini technology page.Gemini Nano is expanding beyond text-only inputs to include images as well. Starting with Pixel, applications using Gemini Nano with Multimodality will be able to understand the world the way people do — not just through text, but also through sight, sound and spoken language.Read more about Gemini 1.0 Nano on Android.Today, we’re also sharing a series of updates to Gemma, our family of open models built from the same research and technology used to create the Gemini models.We’re announcing Gemma 2, our next generation of open models for responsible AI innovation. Gemma 2 has a new architecture designed for breakthrough performance and efficiency, and will be available in new sizes.The Gemma family is also expanding with PaliGemma, our first vision-language model inspired by PaLI-3. And we’ve upgraded our Responsible Generative AI Toolkit with LLM Comparator for evaluating the quality of model responses.Read more on the Developer blog.As part of Google DeepMind’s mission to build AI responsibly to benefit humanity, we’ve always wanted to develop universal AI agents that can be helpful in everyday life. That’s why today, we’re sharing our progress in building the future of AI assistants with Project Astra (advanced seeing and talking responsive agent).To be truly useful, an agent needs to understand and respond to the complex and dynamic world just like people do — and take in and remember what it sees and hears to understand context and take action. It also needs to be proactive, teachable and personal, so users can talk to it naturally and without lag or delay.While we’ve made incredible progress developing AI systems that can understand multimodal information, getting response time down to something conversational is a difficult engineering challenge. Over the past few years, we’ve been working to improve how our models perceive, reason and converse to make the pace and quality of interaction feel more natural.Building on Gemini, we’ve developed prototype agents that can process information faster by continuously encoding video frames, combining the video and speech input into a timeline of events, and caching this information for efficient recall.By leveraging our leading speech models, we also enhanced how they sound, giving the agents a wider range of intonations. These agents can better understand the context they’re being used in, and respond quickly, in conversation.With technology like this, it’s easy to envision a future where people could have an expert AI assistant by their side, through a phone or glasses. And some of these capabilities are coming to Google products, like the Gemini app and web experience, later this year.We’ve made incredible progress so far with our family of Gemini models, and we’re always striving to advance the state-of-the-art even further. By investing in a relentless production line of innovation, we’re able to explore new ideas at the frontier, while also unlocking the possibility of new and exciting Gemini use cases.Learn more about Gemini and its capabilities. Your information will be used in accordance with Google’s privacy policy.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>      Done. Just one step more.
    
      Check your inbox to confirm your subscription.
    You are already subscribed to our newsletter.
    You can also subscribe with a
    different email address
    
    .
    
  Let’s stay in touch. Get the latest news from Google in your inbox.
          Follow Us
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://big-culture.github.io//blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[<h3>External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</h3> <p>If you prefer publishing blog posts on medium.com or other external sources, starting version v0.5.0, <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">al-folio</a> lets you to display your external posts in the blog feed of your website! 🎉🎉</p> <p>Configuring external sources of super simple. After upgrading to v0.5.0, just add the following section to your _config.yml:</p> <pre>external_sources:<br />  - name: medium.com  # name of the source (arbitrary string)<br />    rss_url: <a href="https://medium.com/@al-folio/feed">https://medium.com/@&lt;your-medium-username&gt;/feed</a></pre> <p>The example above adds your medium.com blog post feed as an external source. But you can add arbitrary RSS feeds as sources.</p> <p>Any questions or suggestions? 👉 Start <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/discussions">a discussion on GitHub</a>!</p> <p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;postId=b60a1d241a0a" width="1" height="1" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>